We all know what a dog means when it wags its tail – it means they’re happy, right?
我们都觉得狗狗摇尾巴就是开心的意思，对吧？
Well, maybe not according to leading animal psychologists who analyse what a dog may be or may not be feeling.
但研究狗狗情绪的顶尖动物心理学家却表示，事情可能并非如此。
There may be more of a tale in the movements of a dog’s tail than most of us think.
狗狗尾巴的摆动里，藏着的门道可能远比我们想象的要多。
Most of us agree that it would probably make life whole lot easier and fun if dogs could actually converse rather than bark with us, but sadly they have not yet evolved to develop that skill.
想必大家都认同，要是狗狗能开口跟我们聊天，而不是只会汪汪叫，生活或许会轻松有趣得多。可惜的是，它们还没进化出这种能力。
There are some obvious signs of what your pooch is thinking.
不过狗狗的一些想法，还是能通过明显的信号看出来。
For example, growling could show aggression, scratching at the door could mean a call of nature, and rolling on their backs could show submission.
比如，低吼可能代表攻击性，抓门可能是想上厕所，翻身露肚皮则可能是表示顺从。
However, in the opinions of experts like Stanley Coren, professor of psychology at the University of British Colombia, your canine companion may be trying to tell you much more with the movements and position of their tails.
但英属哥伦比亚大学心理学教授斯坦利·科伦等专家认为，狗狗的尾巴摆动方式和位置，可能还在向你传递更多信息。
For example, a broad wag is a friendly sign and can mean that the dog is pleased.
比如，尾巴大幅度摇摆是友好的信号，说明狗狗很开心。
If you see the tail drooping, it may be a sign that the animal is in a state of stress and anxiety. That’s according to Josie F. Turner, a journalist specialised in animal welfare.
专注于动物福利的记者乔西·F·特纳表示，要是狗狗的尾巴耷拉着，可能说明它正处于紧张焦虑的状态。
This is especially obvious if there are whines coming from them, or they are trying to hide.
如果狗狗还伴有呜咽声，或是总想躲起来，那这种状态就更明显了。
It may be time to get them on the leash and take them for that precious ‘w-word’ – walkies.
这时候或许该给它拴上牵引绳，带它去做那件重要的事——散步。
Most dog owners know never to say that word in the vicinity of their four-legged friend, or they will get overly excited forcing you to take them out.
大多数养狗的人都知道，绝对不能在自家毛孩子面前说“散步”这个词，不然它们会兴奋得不行，缠着你带它出门。
A horizontal tail with slight movements may be a sign that your canine is nervous or uncomfortable.
要是狗狗的尾巴平举，还微微晃动，可能说明它感到紧张或不自在。
And the more ample the movements, the more nervous your pooch may be.
尾巴晃动的幅度越大，狗狗可能就越紧张。
Finally, an erect tail accompanied by a swagger in the hips and lots of movement is a sign that your dog is as happy as can be – and very alert.
最后，尾巴竖得笔直，臀部还一扭一扭的，同时尾巴摆动频繁，这说明狗狗处于极度开心的状态，而且十分警觉。
However, if the tail is straight up in the air with no movement, it could be a sign that your dog is alert and trying to exert dominance.
但如果尾巴笔直竖起却一动不动，那就可能是狗狗在保持警觉，并且试图彰显自己的主导地位。
So, the next time you’re greeted by a dog, make sure to have a look and see what their tail is doing.
所以下次遇到狗狗和你打招呼时，记得留意一下它的尾巴动作。
In their own way, they’re trying to tell you if they’re sad, nervous or happy.
狗狗正以自己的方式，告诉你它此刻是难过、紧张还是开心。
Many of us would like to know exactly what they’re thinking. Maybe we should just be grateful their tails are wagging and they’re not plotting our demise.
我们很多人都想确切知道狗狗在想什么，但或许我们应该庆幸它们只是在摇尾巴，而不是在盘算着“算计”我们。